Guide to Ball State University Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00216
Cubberley Education Library
Ball State University (formerly Ball State Teachers College; formerly: Indiana State Normal School, Eastern Division)
1925-1978
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00216
116 item(s)
Located in Muncie, Indiana. Founded in 1918 on land given by the Ball brothers and named the Indiana State Normal School, Eastern Division. In 1922, the name was changed to add "The Ball Teachers College" to the name. By 1929, they had begun calling it Ball State Teachers College. In 1965 the name changed to Ball State University.
Indiana; Teachers colleges
- Indiana State Normal School, Eastern Division, The Ball Teachers College, 1925-1929; 9 item(s) Catalogs for 1925/26, 1927/28-1928/29 Supplement to catalog for 1925/26
  - Indiana State Normal School: Announcements: The Mid-Spring and Summer Terms, 1926-1928; 3 item(s) Annoucements for 1926-1928
  - Educational Aims and Practices in Introduction to Teaching, The Spelling Problem, Integration Through Music, Elimination of Grammatical Speech Errors, and The School and Its Alumni, December, 1925; 1 item(s)
  - Educational Aims and Methods in Supervising Teaching, Kindergarten Teaching, Physical Education, and Silent Reading, March, 1925; 1 item(s)
- Ball State Teachers College, 1929-1965; 93 item(s) Catalogs for 1929/30-1932/33, 1934/35-1949/50, 1951/53-1963/65 Mid-Spring & Summer for 1929-1932, 1935 Schedule of recitations & announcements for 1929/30, 1932/33-1937 Schedule of Classes for 1940, 1946, 1949/50-1959/60, 1961/62-1962/63, 1964/65 Supplement to 1953/55, 1957/59, 1961/63, 1963/65
  - Ball State Teachers College: Report of the President, 1951- 1961; 4 item(s) Reports for the Biennium Ending 1951, 1955, 1957, 1961
  - Burris School, The Laboratory School of Ball State Teachers College, December, 1930; 1 item(s)
  - Ball State Teachers College Bulletin: A Book About Ball State Teachers College, 1933-1954; 5 item(s) Information "prepared for Seniors in the High Schools of Indiana.", 1935-1936 1933 ed. says "A Bulletin of Information for Prospective Students." 1939 ed. says "Concerning Ball State Teachers College" 1954
  - Ball State Teachers College: Graduate Number, June, 1948; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1948
  - Presenting Ball State, November, 1957; 1 item(s)
  - Introducing Ball State, 1963-1964; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1963-1964
  - Ball State Teachers College: A Survey in Pictures, May, 1929; 1 item(s)
  - Ball State Teachers College: Pictorial Bulletin, [1938]; 1 item(s) Rec'd 1938
  - Ball State Teachers College: A Functional Fifth Year of Preparation for Public School Teaching and Administration, September, 1940; 1 item(s)
  - Ball State Teachers College: Summer Schedule, 1951-1963; 11 item(s) Bulletins for 1951-1955, 1957-1958, 1961-1963, 1965
  - Ball State Teachers College: Handbook for Supervising Student Teachers, September, 1958; 1 item(s)
  - A College Seminar to Develop and Evaluate an Improved High School English Program, 1961; 1 item(s)
  - The Emens Years 1945-1968, February, 1968; 1 item(s)
- Ball State University, 1965-1978; 14 item(s) Catalogs for 1965/66, 1968/70-1970/72 Schedule of Classes for 1965/66, 1968/69 Graduate Catalog 1976/77 Undergraduate catalog for 1976/78
  - Introducing Ball State, 1965; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1965
  - Ball State University: Summer Class Schedule, 1966-1968; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1966, 1968
  - Ball State University Faculty Lecture Series, 1967-1969; 2 item(s) Lecture series essays for 1967/68-1968/69
  - Ball State University: College of Architecture and Planning, [1971-1972]; 1 item(s) Brochure for [1971/72]
  - Contemporary Perspectives on Higher Education: Proceedings of University Day, February 7, 1975; 1 item(s)